Should I stomp him?
要我踹死他嗎？
Let's stomp.
一起踹吧
EPISODE 5
（第 5 集）
Why, you--
想幹嘛？
Do you even wash your hands after you pee?
小便之後有沒有洗手啊？
You know how germy our hands are, huh?
你知道我們手上有多少細菌嗎？
E. coli, norovirus, and so much more!
大腸桿菌、諾羅病毒，多到數不清！
Not the stroller!
不准碰嬰兒車！
-Don't kill him. -Why not?
-不要殺他 -為什麼？
A Green Mothers' Society should set an example for a child.
綠色媽咪聯合會要為小孩樹立榜樣嘛
Geez, you're spoiling her.
天哪，你要把她寵上天了
Attention, everyone.
你們都聽好了
Allow me to get rid of your traumatic experience today.
請允許我抹去你們今天的痛苦記憶
Goodness.
天哪
Today, we did not beat you up nor did you come to Myoyeongak.
今天，我們沒有打你們 你們也沒有來過妙緣閣
Look what we have here.
看看這是什麼
We have another Yeon, huh?
還有另一個阿硯嗎？
Ah-eum.
峨音
You're the one who still grieves for that woman.
你是那個還在為那個女人悲痛的阿硯
While I stand here facing you.
而我就站在你面前
Just die.
去死吧
Wait.
等一下
Please don't go.
求妳不要走
I missed you.
我想妳了
I missed you so much, I thought I'd lose my mind.
我想妳想到快要瘋了
Don't ever leave me again…
再也不要離開我了…
Ah-eum.
峨音
Damn it.
該死
What was I expecting?
我還抱有什麼幻想啊？
Moo-yeong has returned.
無影回來了
Do you remember?
記得嗎？
When the three of us used to race, you always came in first.
從前我們三個賽跑的時候 你總是第一名
I always watched you as I ran.
我總是一邊跑一邊看你
Only you.
眼裡只有你
Just like then…
就像當初一樣…
I only seem to be watching you walk away.
我似乎只能看著你離我而去
Hong-joo?
紅朱？
Good night, Yeon of the year 1938.
晚安，1938年的阿硯
You're him, aren't you?
你是那個人對不對？
-Wait. What do you mean? -You can't fool me.
-等等，什麼意思？ -你休想騙我
You stole all the jewelry from my house!
你從我家偷走了所有的珠寶！
You have proof? You don't have CCTV here, no?
妳有證據嗎？這裡沒有監視器吧？
CC… Oh.
監…我知道了
So that's how you want to play?
原來你想這樣玩啊？
You'll be on the front page tomorrow.
你要登上明天的頭版新聞了
"The thief who robbed seven homes of gold mining royalty."
“打劫擁有金礦開採權的 七大家族的小偷”
-No, the other houses weren't me! -Did you just confess?
-不對，其他幾家不是我偷的！ -你這是認罪了嗎？
Damn it.
該死
Give me the camera. You don't have my image rights!
給我照相機 妳沒有權力使用我的肖像！
-Give me this shirt! -Give me the camera!
-把這件襯衫還給我！ -給我照相機！
Give me the--
給我…
-Gosh, what are you doing? -Give it. Give it to me!
-天哪，妳做什麼？ -給我，還給我！
Damn it!
該死！
What are you?
你是什麼東西？
How are you fine after getting shot?
中彈後居然沒事？
Well, it's something like…
這就像是…
It's like my specialty. I don't seem to die from gun shots.
這是我的專長啦 我好像不會被子彈打死
This gun wound…
這處槍傷…
I don't believe you, but if you're speaking the truth…
我不相信你，但如果你講的是真話
What's your opinion on Japanese imperialism?
你怎麼看日本帝國主義？
What?
什麼？
Why would the Governor-General want Mi-ho?
總督為什麼要抓美好？
If the reward is enough to buy a house, this is serious, right?
如果說獎金足以買一棟房屋 這件事就嚴重了，對不對？
Want to see something?
你想看一樣東西嗎？
Now, guess where it is.
猜猜它在哪裡
-What the-- Huh? -Okay. One more time.
-什麼？ -好的，再來一次
What's this? She gets it right every time.
怎麼回事？她每次都猜中了
They say a foundling brings fortune, but she's a natural gambler.
都說棄嬰可以招財納福 她簡直是賭博天才啊
You'll bring me a mountain of wealth, right?
妳會幫我帶來數不盡的財富 對不對？
Wait a minute…
等一下…
Wealth and fortune…
招財納福…
Could she be a "fortune god"?
她不會是“財神”吧？
FORTUNE GOD - INDIGENOUS GOD BRINGING FORTUNE
（財神：招財納福的本土神）
They say a fortune god chooses where they will nest.
據說財神會擇址安家
Whenever we left her elsewhere, she kept coming back.
我們每次把她丟在別處 她都自己回來了
Don't they usually nest underground? As a snake or a toad with no face.
財神不是通常在地下安家嗎？ 以沒有臉的蛇或蟾蜍的形象出現
Who are you? Huh? Tell me.
妳是誰啊？告訴我嘛
It's only a matter of time before the Governor-General finds us.
總督找到我們是早晚的事
Red-white mask is coming, too.
紅白面具人也會來的
Is staying here the best choice for her well-being?
對她來說 留在這裡是最好的選擇嗎？
Jung Dae-seung from Jongno Station?
鐘路派出所的鄭大勝？
That snake tried to use us as human shields.
那個惡毒的傢伙想拿我們當人盾
With Madame Ryu absent, where did you go in all this mess?
柳閣長不在 這裡亂成一團的時候，妳上哪去了？
What's this? Did Apricot report on us?
怎麼了？是杏子告發我們的嗎？
No. I didn't tell anyone about the baby.
不是，我沒有跟任何人講過女嬰的事
You fool. Do you think she's you?
傻瓜，妳以為她和妳一樣蠢嗎？
Don't insult me, you idiot!
白痴，不准侮辱我！
-Did you just pinch me? -Ouch!
-妳竟敢掐我？ -好痛！
Why do you all look like hell?
你們為什麼這麼狼狽？
We ran into an enormous tiger, while on the baby search.
我們尋找嬰兒的路上遇到一頭巨虎
It said, "Give me some tteok," so I gave it some but it didn't want it.
牠說：“我要吃米糕” 我給了牠，但是牠不要
It preferred honeyed flavors…
牠更喜歡蜂蜜味的…
-Have you gone mad? -I'm telling the truth, sir.
-你瘋了嗎？ -我講的是實話，長官
Right, guys?
你們說對不對？
-Yes, he's right. -That's what happened.
-他講得對 -是這樣沒錯
It was a tiger, sir.
是一隻老虎，長官
You must have been possessed by something.
你一定是被某種東西附體了
Something that's not a human.
某種非人的東西
Who are you?
你是誰？
I found the baby's location. She's at Myoyeongak.
我找到那個嬰兒的下落了 她在妙緣閣
-I'll go get her right away. -Not on your own.
-我現在就去抓她來 -你一個人還不夠
There's a pretty strong Joseon demon there.
那裡有非常強大的朝鮮妖怪
I'll go there myself.
我要親自出馬
You shouldn't be seen entering a gisaeng house.
不能讓人看到您走進妓生館
Your identity could be compromised…
當心暴露身份…
The owner of Myoyeongak, she's the woman you met on the train?
妙緣閣的閣長 是你在列車上見到的女人嗎？
-Yes, sir. -Use her.
-是的 -好好利用她
I know that bitch's weakness.
我知道那個賤人的弱點
My sister is a gisaeng there.
我妹妹是那裡的妓生
Confirm his statement.
去確認他的說法
Oh, I also heard that someone gave out a ton of gold in the slums.
我還聽說 有人在貧民窟捐出了一噸黃金
Where?
在哪裡？
Where will you go, ma'am?
閣長要去哪裡？
-To Lord Lee Yeon or Lord Moo-yeong? -I'm not sure.
-去找李硯大人還是無影大人？ -我也不知道
They were the only friends I had my entire life…
我從小到大只有他們兩個朋友…
-My dear friends are about to start a war. -Please don't interfere.
-而我最親近的朋友們卻要開戰了 -請閣長不要插手
One way or the other, you'll end up getting hurt, ma'am.
不管怎樣，閣長最終都會受傷的
No. I must be the one to do it.
不，我必須插手
Perhaps…
也許…
I may have to kill one of them with my own hands.
我不得不親手殺死他們其中一個
Have a drink.
喝酒吧
Isn't it hard working for me?
在我手下效力很辛苦吧？
It's already been 17 years, since I first met you, ma'am.
我認識閣長十七年了
If it weren't for you, I would've died at the hands of those Japanese soldiers.
如果沒有閣長 我已經死在那些日本兵手裡了
Many native dogs continue to be killed, due to the Stray Dog Slaughter Act.
殺野狗行動導致很多本土犬接連被殺
STRAY DOG SLAUGHTER ACT
（殺野狗行動）
ACT THAT SLAUGHTERED 1.5 MILLION DOGS FOR FUR AND LEATHER IN WAR
（戰爭時期，為獲取皮毛和皮革 屠殺一百五十萬隻狗的行動）
When I was a mountain god,
我做山神的時候
humans used to come bearing grain to invoke my favor.
人類常常帶著糧食來求我護佑
At first, I granted every wish just to look good.
起初，我會為了形象滿足所有的願望
But getting everything for nothing was what made humans so weak and evil.
但是不勞而獲 使人類變得特別軟弱和邪惡
You always said so,
閣長經常說
"We are not the protagonists in the human world."
“我們不是人類世界的主人公”
We must fight our own battles.
大家必須打自己的仗
Humans, and us likewise.
人類如此，我們也是如此
My battlefield is here.
我的戰場就在這裡
I will serve one master until the day I die.
我會至死效忠唯一的主人
-Look everywhere! -Yes, sir!
-全部搜一遍！ -是！
Search everywhere!
每個地方都要搜！
Hey, have you searched there yet? What about here?
那邊搜過了嗎？這裡呢？
Hurry up!
快點！
-Searched here yet? -Search thoroughly.
-這裡搜過嗎？ -仔細搜
Please have mercy!
求你饒命啊！
Have mercy.
饒命
The fragrant smell of blood.
鮮血的芳香
Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
Did you run around all shirtless? It's disgusting--
你光著身體到處跑嗎？很噁心…
-Look who I brought. -You guys work together?
-你看我帶誰來了 -你們是一夥的？
Why would you bring our victim here?
幹嘛把受害者帶過來？
I got caught, but we made amends.
我被抓住了，但我已經賠罪了
I thought you were a detective. Do detectives steal too?
你不是偵探嗎？偵探也偷東西嗎？
Well, it was an inevitable situation. I hope you try to understand.
我也是身不由己，請妳盡量理解一下
Where's your modesty?
舉止莊重點好不好？
-I saved your life. -Whoa, whoa.
-我救過妳的命 -冷靜點嘛
-Hand over the stolen jewels. -Oh, wait here a moment.
-把偷走的珠寶交出來 -請在這裡等一下
-Hey, not the golden ruler. -Yes, I know.
-不能把金尺給她 -我知道
And the police are scouring for Mi-ho right now.
而且警察還在到處搜尋美好
We can trust her. She fights for independence.
我們可以信任她，她是獨立運動份子
You thieves raise a baby too? You steal her too?
你們小偷也養小孩嗎？ 她也是你們偷來的？
-You a martial arts master? -What are you on about?
-妳是武林高手嗎？ -你在說什麼？
Then don't push it with me.
那就不要惹怒我
-I'll make mincemeat out of you. -What did you say, punk?
-小心我把妳做成肉餡 -混蛋，你說什麼？
The ruler made of gold is gone. I wonder where it went?
那把黃金做的尺子不見了 哪裡去了呢？
I'll make up for it.
我會賠償妳的
Gosh, I love Gyeongseong the most.
天哪，我最喜歡京城了
Look at their demeanor. They're from an organization.
看他們的舉止是有組織的
You the Madame of Myoyeongak? The Governor-General has summoned you.
是妙緣閣的閣長嗎？總督要召見妳
I'll be back.
我去去就回
Have you thought about my proposal?
你有考慮過我的提議嗎？
Let me just ask one thing: Why the independence movement?
我只問妳一個問題 為什麼參加獨立運動？
With this much wealth, you can shop and golf for the rest of your life, no?
這些財富不是足夠妳一輩子 盡情購物、打高爾夫了嗎？
At first, I started to dig into my sister's death.
一開始我只想調查姊姊的死亡
Then, I wanted my patriotism
後來，我想用我的愛國之心
to repay for my father's treacheries.
彌補父親叛國的罪行
Eventually, I made comrades,
最後，我有了一些同志
and heard of a comrade's death almost every day.
幾乎每天都會聽說同志的死訊
Even with all this wealth, I'm still in debt.
即使擁有這些財富，我依然欠著債
Because I survived.
因為我活下來了
Why did you pick me?
妳為什麼選中我？
I'm in the spotlight due to family circumstances, and you…
因為家庭的原因 我是眾人矚目的焦點，而你…
REWARD: ONE-MILLION-WON
（懸賞尋人：一萬朝鮮圓）
…have a secret to keep.
…有個祕密需要保守
You in or out?
你加不加入？
In this era of Joseon's disarray,
在朝鮮這個混亂的時代
I was merely busy taking care of an opium addict.
我只忙著照顧一個吸鴉片的癮君子
That always bothered me.
這一直讓我於心不安
Who knew I'd arrive in the year 1938,
誰知道我會來到1938年
and meet an activist who happens to look just like my wife.
見到一個剛好和我老婆 長得一樣的獨立份子呢
It must be fate.
一定是命運的安排
Gyeongseong Station tonight.
今晚去京城站
A man will come, holding a white chrysanthemum.
會有一個手持白菊花的男人過來
Since I've already been robbed, let's just fund our war chest.
既然我已經被打劫了 就用它來資助我們的戰爭吧
What do I do… I think I might get neurosis.
怎麼辦？我可能要發神經了
Can you play the piano?
你會彈鋼琴嗎？
Not really, I…
不怎麼會，我…
I can only play do-re-mi-re-do.
我只會彈do-re-mi-re-do
Handle it carefully, comrade.
小心拿好，同志
Comrade?
同志？
Comrade…
同志…
Pleasure to meet you. I am Chief Commissioner, Ryuhei Kato.
幸會，我是首席專員加藤龍平
-The reason for this is-- -I heard it on my way.
-請閣長過來是因為… -我在路上聽說了
I hear it's because of a wanted baby. And she's at Myoyeongak.
據說是為了找一個嬰兒 而她人在妙緣閣
It seems we'll get along well.
看來我們會相處得很融洽
A bothersome jerk seems to have it.
嬰兒似乎在一個討人厭的混蛋手中
But will Madame Ryu hand it over?
柳閣長願意把她交出來嗎？
How much do you know about me?
你對我瞭解多少？
The woman wielding Gyeongseong's funds and information in her palm.
一個手握京城資金和情報的女人
But strangely so…
但奇怪的是…
Someone who never seems to age.
她似乎永遠不會老
The very woman of such whispers.
這些傳聞中的女人正是妳
Well, you see… I have a pretty intense beauty regimen.
我有強大的美容養生之道
Well, I heard something different.
我聽說過另一種解釋
We met on the train, no?
我們在列車上見過吧？
Damn it.
該死
What did you want with me?
你想怎樣？
As you can see, she's a demon.
總督也看到了，她是妖怪
-I already knew what you were. -If so…
-我早就知道妳是什麼東西了 -既然如此…
You must know you can't threaten me like this.
你一定知道不能這樣威脅我
That's why…
所以…
we've prepared a small gift.
我們準備了一份薄禮
-Who are you? -You like the gayageum, no?
-妳是誰？ -你喜歡伽倻琴是吧？
That's a familiar face.
是一張熟悉的面孔
The wound is presumed to be caused by an instrument string.
傷口像是樂器的弦造成的
A gayageum, perhaps?
也許是伽倻琴？
I hear he got into a dispute with a gayageum-playing gisaeng that day.
聽說那一天 他和一位彈奏伽倻琴的妓生起過爭執
Her name was…
她叫…
Orchid, I believe?
蘭草吧？
She confessed before we even plucked her nails.
我們還沒有拔掉她的指甲 她就認罪了
-That she killed him. -What?
-她承認是她殺了他 -什麼？
She killed a soldier, so she'll be shot to death.
她殺害了一位士兵，必須被槍斃
And Myoyeongak will be shut down.
而妙緣閣也會被關閉
Where is Orchid?
蘭草在哪裡？
Bring the baby and make the fortune god talk.
交出那個嬰兒，讓財神乖乖開口
If I don't have the gold mine map by noon tomorrow,
如果我明天中午之前拿不到金礦地圖
that girl will die.
那個女人就會死
-Start the car. -Is this the only way?
-出發 -沒別的辦法嗎？
Everything I've built in the human world is here.
我在人類世界建造的一切都在這裡了
I will save Orchid and protect Myoyeongak.
我要營救蘭草，保護妙緣閣
The woman has the baby.
嬰兒在那個女人手上了
Head over to Myoyeongak and check on their reaction.
你去妙緣閣看看他們的反應
As long as we have the hostage, they won't move carelessly.
只要我們有人質在手 他們就不會輕舉妄動
That woman is not to be underestimated.
不要低估那個女人
-Mi-ho!
-美好！
Mi-ho!
美好！
-She's not here. Where did our Mi-ho go? -Maybe Lord Lee Rang took her out?
-她不在這裡，我們美好人呢？ -也許李朗大人帶她出去了？
No, he went to gather his men.
不會的，他去召集手下了
-I don't see Orchid, either. -What?
-蘭草也不見了 -什麼？
She went to the bath house, but she never returned.
她去澡堂後，一直沒有回來
What the hell is--
這究竟是…
Say it again.
再講一遍
If you find the kidnapped Orchid, she'll tell you the baby's location.
找到被綁架的蘭草 她會告訴你嬰兒在哪裡
Where is Hong-joo right now?
紅朱在哪裡？
-Tell me! -Please find Orchid.
-告訴我！ -拜託你找到蘭草
That's all I have to say.
我只能說這麼多
Whoa! Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
Move. I'm going to make him talk.
讓開，我要打到他開口
Move the gisaeng, Orchid. If you don't hear from me by noon--
把妓生蘭草帶走 如果中午還沒接到我的命令…
You're telling me to shoot her, right?
我就槍斃她，對不對？
The gold mines…
金礦的事情…
How bitter!
好苦！
I'm going to count to three.
我數到三
Tell me where the gold mine is.
告訴我金礦在哪裡
One. Two…
一、二…
-Three-- -Move.
-三… -讓開
I don't know how you lost her,
我不知道你是怎麼弄丟她的
but she was loved.
但是她被照顧得很好
The three men staying at my home may be clumsy,
住在我家的三個男人笨手笨腳
but they took care of her sincerely.
但他們都有真心實意地照顧她
A human's life depends on you.
一條人命掌握在你手上
Please help.
拜託你幫幫忙
Thank you.
謝謝
Here.
這裡
That's not a mine?
那不是礦山吧？
Gold can also be found in the river.
河裡也可能有金礦
-Check if it's there. -Yes, sir.
-去看看 -是
Come with us.
跟我們一起去
-Why should I? -Whether humans or demons,
-為什麼？ -人類也好，妖怪也好
I can't trust you Joseon pricks.
我都信不過你們這些朝鮮混帳
-Where is Orchid right now? -Hey! Do you want to see me get fired?
-蘭草在哪裡？ -妳想看我被開除嗎？
Who do you think I'm doing this for?
妳以為我這樣做都是為了誰？
-You killed her! -That's not it!
-你把她殺了！ -沒有啦！
Goodness.
真是的
Fine. Watch your only sister die and live a good life.
好啊，看著你唯一的妹妹死在你面前 好好過你的人生吧
-Give that to me! -Where is Orchid?
-把槍給我！ -蘭草在哪裡？
-Gosh, we're in a pickle. -Why Jongno Police Station of all places?
-天哪，這次麻煩大了 -為什麼偏偏是鐘路派出所？
Should we just force ourselves in?
要不要硬闖進去？
Roughly how many people are inside a police station?
一個派出所裡面大概有多少人？
-I don't know. At least 250 people? -250?
-我不知道，至少250個吧？ -250？
We have 45 minutes until noon.
還有四十五分鐘就到中午了
-We've no time for this. -What about Lord Lee Rang?
-我們沒時間猶豫了 -李朗大人呢？
-He's going to help Hong-joo. -Then what do we do?
-他要去幫紅朱 -那我們怎麼辦？
How about this?
這樣吧
No, even if my life depended on it!
不行，即便要了我的命都不行！
Shall I do it then? Me, the former mountain god?
那要我去嗎？我可是前任山神啊
-I must save my dignity! -On about that again, huh?
-必須保住尊嚴 -又是這套？
-You idiot! -Stop right there!
-白痴！ -站住！
-Just be confident. -Right. We're taking over Jongno Station.
-自信一點 -是啊，我們要拿下鐘路派出所
Hey, can you speak Japanese?
你會講日語嗎？
-I studied at an academy for six months. -Oh?
-我在一所學校學過六個月 -是嗎？
-It means? -"Can I get a refund?"
-什麼意思？ -“可以退款嗎？”
-Geez. -Don't be scared. Half of 'em are Korean.
-真是的 -別怕，他們有一半是朝鮮人
You two look unfamiliar.
你們兩個看起來是生面孔
Oh, we're new here, sir.
長官，我們是新來的
-Are you two Korean? -Yes, sir!
-你們兩個是朝鮮人嗎？ -是！
-I am Korean too. -Yes, sir…
-我也是朝鮮人 -是
But have we met before?
話說回來，我們以前見過嗎？
Well…
這個…
I often hear that I have a common face.
大家常說我長著一張大眾臉
-Your face is common? -Yes.
-你這也算大眾臉？ -是啊
Anyway, keep up the good work.
好吧，繼續努力
Wait.
等一下
You're new, so I guess you wouldn't know.
你們是新來的，還不知道吧
I-- I have to shave my head? Why? Hair's everything to a man.
我得剃髮嗎？ 為什麼？頭髮是男人的命根子啊
The war is to be prolonged.
戰爭還要持續一段時間
A SHAVING DECREE WAS MADE TO POLICEMEN IN 1938
（1938年頒布了警察剃髮法令）
An expression of our devotion even on the home front.
這是為了表達 我們後方人員的赤誠之心
It means to establish your resolve.
是堅定決心的象徵
Oh, my resolve…
我的決心啊…
Here. Allow me, sir!
來，我幫你！
I was an intern at Choi Seung-ja Hair Salon.
我在崔勝子美容院做過實習生
Not this time, sir.
這次不行
Take a seat.
坐吧
Okay.
好的
Oh, look. I snipped it off.
看，我把它剪掉了
20 MINUTES UNTIL NOON
（距離中午還剩20分鐘）
Let's go. Go.
我們走，快點
Take a close look. Okay?
仔細找，知道嗎？
-Yes, sir. -Yes, sir!
-是 -是！
-If you see anything sparkle, tell me! -Yes, sir.
-看到閃閃發亮的東西就向我匯報！ -是
-You see anything? -No, no. There's nothing here.
-有看到什麼嗎？ -沒有，這裡什麼都沒有
For goodness' sake.
我的天
I can't believe I'm only here to babysit.
真不敢相信我是來照顧小孩的
You sure you're related to Apricot?
你真的是杏子的親戚嗎？
Why? Is she ashamed that her brother is a sellout?
怎麼了？她沒臉說她哥哥是叛徒嗎？
I know policemen don't earn much, but you send her money every month, no?
我知道警察的薪水不高 但是你每個月都有送錢給她吧？
-It's so endearing, I can't stand it. -Hey, that's enough!
-這麼體貼，真讓人受不了 -夠了！
If it wasn't for her, I'd have raided your place a dozen times!
假如沒有她 我不知道查抄妳那裡多少次了！
If you weren't her brother, this would be your grave.
假如你不是她哥哥 你早就死在這裡了
Look at you all smiling, without a clue in the world. Goodness.
看妳笑得多開心 完全不知人間疾苦，真是的
Don't smile, kid.
別笑了，小孩
If they don't find any gold today, you and your dad are dead, you punk.
如果他們今天找不到黃金 妳和妳爸爸都會死的，臭丫頭
My goodness.
天哪
Why this little brat!
這個臭丫頭居然戳人！
Look here! She just flicked me off, no?
看！她剛剛是在對我豎中指嗎？
You have no filter, indeed.
你果然是真性情
There's no gold, sir!
長官，沒有黃金！
Get up.
起來
You dare fool me?
你竟敢騙我？
-What? -Huh?
-什麼？ -啊？
What are you all doing? Go check it out!
你們愣著做什麼？過去看看！
Hey, hurry up and just--
快點…
-Whoa! -Oh-- Oh!
-哇！ -喔！
What's that?
那是什麼？
Come here!
過來！
It's gold…
是黃金…
I found gold!
我找到黃金了！
Hey, carrot!
賞他紅蘿蔔！
Is it really gold?
真的是黃金嗎？
Hey, get up!
喂，起來！
Wake up, wake up!
醒醒！
The governor's office offered a deal.
總督府提出一項交易
If I don't bring the baby, Orchid will die.
如果我不把嬰兒送過去，蘭草就會死
So what's your choice?
那妳怎麼選？
I've already made my choice.
我已經選好了
Hey, go to sleep.
乖，睡吧
Then, how about this?
那…這樣可以嗎？
Why don't you do the disguise?
為什麼不是你偽裝？
Please hang in there until we save Orchid. You've been doing the disguises anyway.
堅持到我們救出蘭草就好啦 反正一直是你偽裝嘛
Only the three of us know about this operation, okay?
這次行動 只有我們三人知道，明白嗎？
Hey, your hair looks fine.
你的髮型沒問題啦
-Where the hell are we? -We're the police, so march down and ask.
-這到底是哪裡啊？ -我們是警察，光明正大地過去問吧
-Over there! -I only need to ask, right? Hey.
-有人來了！ -直接問嗎？喂
Where's the geisha from Myoyeongak? I have orders to move her.
從妙緣閣抓來的藝妓在哪裡？ 上面命令我帶她走
-To where? -The Governor-General.
-去哪裡？ -總督那裡
I see. Check the interrogation room.
這樣啊，你去審訊室看看
We go downstairs? Hey, we have 10 minutes left!
要去樓下嗎？我們還剩十分鐘！
Move it!
快走！
You, come here.
你過來
Lee Yeon? Aren't you Lee Yeon?
李硯？你不是李硯嗎？
-Who were they again? -The disguised raccoon couple.
-他們是誰來著？ -偽裝成人類的浣熊夫婦
Why are you here pretending to be the police?
你為什麼在這裡假扮警察？
It's all your fault!
都怪你！
-We got detained handing this out! -Silence!
-我們分發傳單的時候被抓了！ -安靜！
-You-- -You know them?
-你… -你認識他們？
Yes, they were mine to catch, so they seem to have a grudge on me.
是的，是我要抓他們的 所以他們懷恨在心
-Why you nine-tailed fox-- -Hey!
-你這隻九尾狐… -嘿！
-A fox? -He's hallucinating. He's an opium addict.
-狐狸？ -他出現幻覺了，他有鴉片癮
Look at his eyes. Look here!
你看他的眼睛，看這裡！
-You're the addi-- -That's enough. Take them away!
-是你有鴉… -夠了，把他們帶走！
The new guys are quite passionate, huh?
新來的警察很熱心嘛
Orchid, are you okay?
蘭草，妳還好嗎？
-Wake up. -Gosh, those bastards.
-醒醒 -天哪，那些混帳
How could they do this to her?
竟敢把她傷成這樣？
Lord Lee Yeon?
李硯大人？
-Shin-ju's here too? -Yeah.
-申炷也來了？ -是啊
-Can you get up? Let's go. -No.
-妳能站起來嗎？我們走吧 -不行
If I run away, Madame Ryu will be in danger.
如果我跑了，柳閣長會有危險
Do you know what she's done to save you?
妳知道為了救妳，紅朱做了什麼嗎？
Get up. We don't have much time.
起來吧，我們的時間不多了
This way.
這邊
Walk straight!
好好走！
-Where's this geisha named Orchid? -Governor-General's orders to move her.
-名叫蘭草的藝妓在哪裡？ -總督下令帶她走
Some other guys already came for her, though.
可是已經有人來帶走她了
Hmm…
嗯…
-Hey. Hey! -Hey!
-喂！
Hey, stop right there!
站住！
Stop them!
攔住他們！
All that comes up is sand.
挖上來的都是沙子
-Keep your eyes open! -Yes, sir.
-睜大眼睛！ -是
Tell me if you see anything sparkle!
看到閃閃發亮的東西就向我匯報！
Hurry and dig!
快點挖！
Excuse me, sir. I think we need more people.
長官，我覺得我們需要增添人手
-Then we-- -You'll finish by today, no matter what.
-那樣的話，我們… -無論如何，你們今天必須挖完
-Understood, sir. -Yes!
-是，長官 -是！
Hurry up!
快點！
Where did the baby go? You're not even watching her. Gosh!
那個嬰兒呢？ 妳都沒有看著她！真是的！
Where are you going, huh?
妳要去哪裡啊？
Goodness, there you are. Where'd you think you're going?
天哪，抓到妳了，妳想去哪裡？
Put me down, you damn cop.
放我下來，死警察
Can you… talk?
妳會…講話？
It's a secret. Come closer.
這是祕密，靠近一點
-Screw you! -Ouch!
-去你的！ -哎唷！
Ow, that hurts!
好痛！
Goodness.
天哪
Come here, you.
過來吧
-Hey, control your temper. -It's all your fault.
-你控制一下脾氣啊 -還不都要怪妳
Will there be more gold?
還有黃金嗎？
-This baby bites people! -Yeah, kids are like that.
-這個嬰兒會咬人！ -小孩子就是這樣啦
-No, I mean she called me a cop! -Stop being ridiculous.
-不是，她還叫我警察！ -別說傻話了
But she talks so well!
可是她話講得很流利啊！
Hey.
喂
Point out all the gold mines.
指出所有的金礦
Oh-- Oh, wait. Slow down.
等等，慢一點
-Are you sure? -Yes, sir.
-你確定嗎？ -確定，長官
It includes a gold mine being developed in secret.
其中包括一座正在祕密開採的金礦
This guy is the real deal.
這傢伙名副其實
Is that so?
是嗎？
No, not yet.
不行，還不行
We must save Orchid first.
我們必須先救蘭草
Yeon, hurry up.
阿硯，快一點
-Stop there! -Get 'em!
-站住！ -抓住他們！
-Hold on! -Don't let them get away!
-等等！ -別讓他們跑掉！
Catch 'em!
抓住他們！
-Stop, stop! -Catch them!
-站住！ -抓住他們！
Get 'em!
抓住他們！
-Go on ahead. I'll distract them. -Okay.
-你們先走，我來引開他們 -好的
Hey, arrest me.
逮捕我吧
Where do you think you're touching, you bastard!
混帳，你往哪裡摸啊？
What the hell are you?
妳到底是什麼東西？
Die!
去死！
Geez. Die, just die!
真是的，去死吧！
Gosh, you make my skin crawl!
天哪，你害我雞皮疙瘩都起來了！
Damn it.
該死
This is why I hate disguises.
所以說我討厭偽裝嘛
-Lord Lee Yeon! -Those pricks touched my-- Forget it.
-李硯大人！ -這些混帳摸我的…算了
But how do we tell them Orchid is safe? We don't even have cell phones.
我們要怎麼通知他們蘭草安全了？ 我們連手機都沒有
Hold on.
等一下
What the hell? What's with the weather, huh?
搞什麼？怎麼突然變天了？
It's a sign from Yeon. Orchid is safe.
是阿硯的訊號，蘭草安全了
-Give this to the Chief Commissioner now. -Yes, sir.
-立刻把地圖交給首席專員 -是
With this much gold, a Hundred-Year-War sounds cheap!
有了這些黃金 資助百年戰爭也不在話下！
-If we're done here, I'll be off. -Not interested what happens to the kid?
-任務已完成，我先告辭了 -妳不好奇我如何處置這個小孩嗎？
I'm not really a humanist, you know.
你也知道，我不是人道主義者
That bitch dares to betray me?
這個賤人竟敢背叛我？
Sorry, but I can't have the map fall into their hands.
對不起 我不能任由地圖落入他們手中
Your dad is dead. So you'd become a begrudging demon, no?
妳爸爸死了 妳會變成一個心懷仇恨的妖怪吧？
Geez. Thought I'd suffocate, all squished in there.
天哪，擠在那裡面，差點憋死我
-Who are you? -Me?
-你是誰？ -我嗎？
I'm Joseon's nine-tailed fox.
朝鮮九尾狐
Everyone, freeze!
誰都不准動！
One more step and this will be your cemetery.
只要邁一步 這就會成為你們的葬身之地
Hey, fox-in-law. I'll have your back. Go for it.
狐狸小叔，我保護你，放心衝吧
-Will Lord Lee Rang be okay? -He has Hong-joo.
-李朗大人不會有事吧？ -有紅朱保護他
I'll take Orchid to Myoyeongak. What about our Mi-ho?
我送蘭草回妙緣閣 我們美好怎麼辦？
I left her with Water Snail Bride. I'll go get her.
我把她放在田螺姑娘那裡了 我會去接她的
What's this?
這是什麼？
He reeks of blood.
他渾身都是血腥味
Was there a demon in Joseon with this much power?
朝鮮居然有如此強大的妖怪？
What're you looking at?
你看什麼？
-What's your name? -Lee Yeon.
-你叫什麼名字？ -李硯
My name is Ryuhei Kato. Remember it. We'll meet again.
我叫加藤龍平 記住這名字，我們還會見面的
You better stop eating humans.
你最好不要再吃人了
Or else your head might fly off.
不然可能會掉腦袋
-Lord Lee Yeon! -Don't come!
-李硯大人！ -不要過來！
Lee Yeon.
李硯
You did well.
辛苦妳了
Madame, I'll never forget what you've done for me.
閣長，我永遠不會忘記妳的大恩
It was nothing.
沒什麼啦
You almost lost everything because of me.
我差點害妳失去一切
You idiot.
傻瓜
Why did you say you killed him? You should've said it was me.
為什麼承認是妳殺了他？ 妳應該說是我殺的
I wanted to protect you, ma'am.
我想保護妳，閣長
As you've always protected us.
就像妳一直保護我們一樣
You're back, ma'am.
主人，妳回來了
Perhaps, our Mi-ho is--
我們美好不會是…
-She is the fortune god. -Huh?
-她是財神 -啊？
-She's not your daughter? -I just pull petty tricks,
-她不是你女兒嗎？ -我只會一些小把戲
but it's my duty to protect her.
我真正的職責是保護她
Why the form of a baby though?
為什麼以嬰兒的模樣見人呢？
As the god who controls desire, she is born in the purest form of a baby,
作為掌控慾望的神 她生來便是最純潔的嬰兒模樣
and never grows old.
永遠不會長大
That's too harsh on the child.
這個小孩太辛苦了吧
It's her destiny as an indigenous god.
這是她作為本土神的宿命啊
-Where will you go now? -I don't know.
-你們現在要去哪裡？ -我不知道
She is the one who decides where to stay or whom to bless.
留在哪裡、賜福什麼人 都是由她決定的
-I packed baby supplies in the bag. -Thank you.
-我在包裡放了嬰兒用品 -謝謝
-Geez. Off you go. -Can I just…
-哎，該走了 -我能不能…
Can I hold her one last time?
我能不能抱她最後一次？
Mi-ho.
美好
I thought my back would break from washing your diapers.
我以為我幫妳洗尿布 會一直洗到腰斷掉
It's already farewells, huh?
沒想到這麼快就要道別了
Wherever you go and whatever name you live by,
無論妳去哪裡，無論妳叫什麼名字
please remember us. But I don't think she will.
一定要記得我們，但我覺得她做不到
Geez, stop being ridiculous.
天哪，別這麼浮誇好嗎
Farewell, okay?
再見啦
It's good to give good fortune to humans, but you be fortunate too.
幫人類招財納福是好事 但妳也要好運喔
Lord Lee Rang, say something too.
李朗大人，你也講兩句吧
I'm good.
不用了
Here, here.
來吧
Yes? Oh, I see.
什麼？這樣啊
What's she saying?
她在說什麼？
She says she prefers the bandit over the doctor.
她說比起這位醫生 她更喜歡這個土匪
Gosh, I knew it.
天哪，我就知道是這樣
Well-- You're not too bad yourself.
那個…妳也不錯啦
Yes?
嗯？
She says you will meet someone you've been grieving.
她說你會遇到你一直在悼念的人
But because of your pure nature, you will lose your way.
但是你本性純潔，會迷失自己的路
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Could you roll up your sleeves?
你可以挽起袖子嗎？
She hopes this will help you find your way.
她希望這個印記能幫你找到自己的路
I'll get going now.
我先告辭了
Goodbye.
再見
Back when we were all poor,
在我們一貧如洗的年代
Joseon people used to take in foundlings to raise as their own.
朝鮮人常常收養棄嬰 當作自己的小孩撫養
-A child who brings good fortune. -Stop crying.
-說他們可以帶來好運 -別哭了
That name saved the lives of many babies from starving to death.
這個美譽幫許多嬰兒 逃過了餓死的惡運
But we met the real foundling.
而我們遇到了真正的棄嬰
Excuse me…
請問…
-Geez, seriously. -May I ask something, sir?
-真是的 -先生，請問一下
I hear there's a pawnshop for demons. Do you know of it?
聽說這裡有一家妖怪當鋪 你知道嗎？
The pawnshop? Of course.
當鋪？當然知道
I bought this there. A fan that lengthens the nose.
這個就是從當鋪買的 可以拉長鼻子的扇子
Don't blabber your mouth to a stranger. This is a harsh world.
不要滔滔不絕地和陌生人講話 這個世道不太平
VICTIMS' CLUB FOR DEMONS VICTIMIZED BY THE FOX
（被這隻狐狸傷害的 妖怪受害者俱樂部）
Do you know Lee Yeon? I'm here to catch him too.
你們認識李硯？我也是來抓他的
Oh, my, my! He's on our side!
天哪！是自己人！
-Are you good at fighting? -Pardon?
-你擅長打架嗎？ -什麼？
What are you doing? Tell him anything at all!
還等什麼？全部告訴他！
Perhaps, you know the location…
當鋪的地址…
The pawnshop for demons only opens on the last day of the month.
妖怪當鋪只在月末最後一天營業
The last day?
最後一天？
I don't have much time… Do you know who owns the place?
我等不了 你知道那裡的店主是誰嗎？
Well, there's a rumor that he's a big shot.
據說是個大人物
-But we're not sure. -Shall we dig around?
-但是不確定 -要我們去打探嗎？
We've got a social butterfly at our meeting.
我們俱樂部有一位交際花
Please do. I'll compensate handsomely…
拜託你們了，我願意重金酬謝…
-No need!
-不需要！
Excuse me…
那個…
Not yet… I still have work left to do.
還不行…我還有任務在身
Father, what's wrong?
爸爸，怎麼了？
Mother, you're awake.
媽媽，妳醒了
The King of Five Paths, right?
你是五道轉輪王吧？
KING OF FIVE PATHS
（五道轉輪王）
THE TENTH KING OF HELL WHO RULES OVER DARKNESS HELL
（掌管暗黑地獄的地獄第十王）
I hate people talking to me when I'm watching movies.
我討厭別人 在我看電影的時候跟我講話
I have something to tell you.
我有事情要告訴你
You can tell me after the movie.
妳可以等電影結束後再講
It's an urgent matter.
事出緊急
I'm not in a hurry.
我不急
I already watched this movie. They all die in the end.
我有看過這部電影 他們最後全部死光了
Why you crazy--
妳這個瘋女人…
-Hey, be quiet! -Gosh.
-安靜！ -天哪
I'm sorry.
對不起
My apologies…
對不起…
You're one heinous being.
妳真的可惡至極
Want to roll around in Darkness Hell?
想去暗黑地獄打滾嗎？
For what crime?
罪名是什麼？
The crime…
罪名是…
of spoiling a movie…
劇透電影情節…
That's nonchargeable.
那不算罪名
A child who shouldn't live has returned alive.
一個不該活著的孩子活著回來了
From the future, at that.
而且是來自未來
Who do you think did it?
你認為是誰幹的？
Impossible.
不可能
Are you questioning the Kings of Hell?
妳是在懷疑地獄十王嗎？
-To be precise, I'm questioning you, sir. -Wh--?
-準確地講，我是在懷疑你 -妳…
Always playing hooky, dipping in and out of the World of the Living.
你總是擅離職守，在陽間進進出出
Playing hooky? Playing hoo--?
擅離職守？擅離…
-What's with him? -Be quiet!
-他怎麼回事啊？ -安靜！
It's not me.
不是我幹的
I must watch movies, run my business. I'm a very busy man.
我必須要看電影、管理地獄 我可是個大忙人
If not the kings, then who?
如果不是十王做的，還能是誰呢？
-The only being with that much power-- -Is you.
-能力如此強大的只有… -妳
There was one other guy too, no?
不是還有一個人嗎？
There's no way he could've done it.
不可能是他幹的
Who's there?
誰在那裡？
You looking for the pawnshop for demons?
你在找妖怪當鋪嗎？
I am…
我是…
the owner of that pawnshop.
那家當鋪的店主
You're the former mountain god of the north, correct?
你是前任的北邊山神吧？
By the looks of it, you're not from this era.
看樣子，你並非這個時代的人
And you're no ordinary merchant.
你也不是普通商人
May I ask for your name?
請問尊姓大名？
I'm the-- Gosh. Do I have to say it myself?
我是…天哪，還要我自己講嗎？
There.
看
Five…
五…
What's "five"?
“五”什麼？
Gosh, you're frustrating.
天哪，你真的煩死人了
The King of Five-- Paths!
五道轉輪…王！
One of the Ten Kings of Hell is here?
地獄十王之一駕到？
Forgive me. I didn't recognize you.
請恕罪，我有眼無珠，沒有認出來
I wonder how such a proper guy has been challenging Taluipa?
這麼有禮貌的人 怎麼會挑戰奪衣婆呢？
I cannot enter your shop, sir. Since you already know everything.
既然您都知道了 我就不能進入您的當鋪了
You're mistaken.
你錯了
Pardon?
什麼？
This is purely a hobby of mine. Let's leave politics out of it.
這完全是我的愛好而已 暫且拋開政治吧
-You mean… -It means I quite like you.
-您是說… -我很喜歡你
So, what is it you want?
說吧，你想要什麼？
I want to reclaim my body.
我想奪回我的身體
Come closer.
靠過來
Taluipa's work, huh?
是奪衣婆的傑作吧？
-This may be quite a hassle. -If you can fix it, I'll do anything.
-這可能很麻煩 -如果您能醫好我，我什麼都願意做
If so, let's take a look.
既然如此，我來看看
Where was it?
放哪去了？
Oh, here it is.
找到了
Cut the yeot, cha, cha, cha Ja-ga-jang, jang, jang!
韓式糖果剪剪剪，切切切！
You don't smile at all. Geez, such an uptight fella.
一點笑容都沒有，真是個拘謹的傢伙
Here.
給你
What will you give me in return?
你要用什麼報答我？
Anything, sir.
什麼都可以，大人
Even my soul.
連我的靈魂都可以
You really don't know who red-white mask is?
妳真的不知道紅白面具人是誰嗎？
How many times must I tell you? I can't see him either!
還要我講多少次？我也看不到他！
-Then, why have those eyes at all? -Gosh, you make my blood boil.
-那妳要這雙千里眼做什麼？ -天哪，我要被你氣炸了
Hey.
喂
So, I'm stuck with you in the future, huh?
未來的我也要和你共事嗎？
Give the future me a heartfelt consolation when you get home.
等你回家後，好好安慰未來的我吧
But I'm saying that I might not be able to go home.
我現在的意思是我可能回不去了
The fortune god said I'll lose my way!
財神說我會迷路的！
Why? Because of the red-white mask!
為什麼？都是因為那個紅白面具人！
The Guardian Stone will pave the way, and the gate will open in time!
守護石會鋪路的 時間之門會及時打開！
Just take care of the stone, you brat.
收好那塊寶石，臭小子
Why are you so indifferent to me?
妳為什麼對我這麼冷漠？
Are you some cyborg in 1938?
妳是1938年的生化人嗎？
Cy-- What?
生什麼？
Gosh, never mind.
天哪，算了
If I don't get home, watch me destroy worlds, Living and Dead!
如果我回不了家 看我還不毀掉陰陽兩界！
Gosh, seriously. I can't believe I traveled here for this.
真是的，我居然為了這個來到這裡
Why are you lying to Yeon?
妳為什麼騙阿硯？
Because it's Moo-yeong… behind that damn red-white mask.
因為該死的紅白面具人是無影
A child born with the fate of a Gemini…
生來帶有雙子宮宿命的孩子…
They say it's either a blessing or a disaster to the world.
據說要麼造福世界，要麼危害世界
But I was confident.
但我當初信心滿懷
That he would become a benevolent mountain god.
相信他會變成仁慈的山神
Yet, you turned him into stone,
可是妳把他變成了石柱
and you were heartbroken for a very long time.
還傷心了很長一段時間
You wept bitter tears. I know that.
妳難受地流過淚，我很清楚
I tried so hard not to get attached.
我已經盡量不讓自己投入感情了
You want to save Moo-yeong, right?
妳想救無影是嗎？
I'm not sure.
我也不知道
I'm just counting on this situation.
只能指望這次時機了
The fact that my future self sent Yeon
未來的我派阿硯
all the way here to catch Moo-yeong…
不辭辛苦地來這裡捉拿無影
must be with good reason.
一定有充分的理由
I'll be back, brother.
哥哥，我會回來的
Going on another date today?
今天又要約會嗎？
He says he'll come to the club.
他說他要來俱樂部找我
-I plan to win his heart over today. -Oh? How so?
-今天我要擄獲他的心 -是嗎？怎麼做？
Magazines say men like women who are good listeners.
雜誌上講，男人喜歡擅於傾聽的女人
Why? What did that punk say?
怎麼？那個臭小子說什麼了？
Something like, "If you want to sing, stand firm on both legs."
他說：“如果妳想唱歌 就兩條腿站穩好好唱
"And not to become a spectacle."
不要出洋相”
That's a first.
這倒是頭一回
For Lee Rang, that brat…
李朗那個臭小子…
Gosh, it's uncomfortable. It's way too uncomfortable.
天哪，好難受，太難受了
-My neck hurts so much. -I'm going.
-我的脖子痛死了 -我先走了
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
-Where are you going at this hour? -I know where he's going.
-這麼晚了要去哪裡呀？ -我知道他要去哪裡
He's going on a date.
去約會
A date?
約會？
I want to go too.
我也想去
Oh, my. What's the occasion?
天哪，今天是什麼日子？
You said to come to the club with a bouquet of flowers. As your second wish.
是妳要我帶一束花來俱樂部的 這是妳的第二個願望
Right…
對喔
-Well, thank you anyway. -Okay. Bye, then.
-還是要謝謝你 -嗯，再見
Hold on.
等一下
You have to watch my show. That's included in the wish.
你必須看我演出才行啊 那也包含在願望裡
Really? Sure, why not.
真的嗎？好啊
-Wow, flowers? -Lord Lee Rang must like her too.
-哇，送花了？ -李朗大人一定也喜歡她
Hey, doesn't she looks so kind?
她看起來很善良吧？
She wants to be a singer, but she's the queen of part-time jobs.
她的夢想是當歌手 但她可說是兼職女王呢
That's great! So they'll be a working married couple.
太好了！ 他們可以當一對努力工作的夫妻
-How old is she? -She's 40 years older than Lord Lee Rang.
-她多大？ -比李朗大人大40歲
That's nothing between demons. They're a perfect match.
對妖怪來講不算什麼 他們是天作之合
You sure you can leave him?
你真的忍心離開他嗎？
Honestly, no.
老實講，不忍心
He's only going to think I abandoned him again.
他會以為我又一次拋棄了他
He never knows how I feel, huh?
他從來不懂我的心
Drinks from the lady over there.
這是那位女士送您的酒
So it's free, right?
那就是免費的嘍？
What do you do for a living?
你是做什麼工作的？
Why do you ask?
問這個做什麼？
You stole a girl's heart.
你偷走了一個女生的心
Perhaps you're a thief?
該不會是小偷吧？
Are you a cop? You raiding my bandit gang?
妳是警察嗎？要突襲我的土匪幫嗎？
Oh, my. You're funny, too!
天哪，沒想到你還這麼幽默呢！
Did she do this?
是她幹的嗎？
Wow. If they quarrel, Lord Lee Rang will be beaten hollow.
哇，如果他們吵架的話 李朗大人會被打得落花流水
-Whoa. -Wow.
-哇
CLUB PARADISE
（樂園俱樂部）
Is this how it ends for us?
我們之間就這樣結束了嗎？
Why did you lie?
妳為什麼騙我？
Sorry, you must be disappointed in me.
對不起，你一定對我很失望吧
-I can't believe I did that… -I liked it.
-我居然做出這種事… -我喜歡
It's much stronger than I thought. Your combat power!
妳的戰鬥力比我想像中強大得多！
Combat power?
戰鬥力？
-It's cool. -Really?
-很酷的 -真的假的？
You're the first one to tell me that!
你是第一個這樣講的人！
-Careful! -He didn't hear it!
-小心點！ -他沒聽到！
Can you run?
妳能跑嗎？
Some annoying guys have caught up with us.
有討厭的傢伙跟上來了
I can run.
我能跑
Gosh, where did they run off to?
天哪，他們跑到哪裡去了？
-They're completely out of sight. -I can't find them at all!
-徹底不見了 -完全找不到！
Are they gone--
他們走了嗎…
They're gone.
他們走了
Shall we go eat together?
我們要一起吃飯嗎？
I'm not sure.
不知道
Only if we're having naengmyeon.
除非吃冷麵
-We got caught because of you. -I can't believe I sneezed right then.
-都是你害我們被發現了 -我居然會在那一刻打噴嚏
-But they're all set to go, right? -Yes. We're done here. Done.
-但是他們已經掃清所有障礙了吧？ -沒錯，我們的任務完成了
I need to see someone real quick.
我要趕去見一個人
-Who? -I have a private life too.
-見誰？ -我也是有私生活的
-Don't wait up. Bye! -Hey, where are you going?
-不用等我，你先睡，再見！ -你要去哪裡？
Gosh, these punks--
天哪，這些臭小子…
Geez. I miss Ji-ah too.
哎，我也想念智雅了
He will definitely come…
他一定會來…
for this treasure.
找這件寶物的
Yeon. Lee Yeon. Come play with me.
阿硯，李硯，來跟我玩啊
What's this?
這是幹嘛？
Cheon Moo-yeong?
千無影？
-Is it really you? -Yes, it's me.
-真的是你嗎？ -是我沒錯
-How are you-- -Alive?
-你怎麼會… -還活著？
Are you red-white mask?
你就是紅白面具人？
It's no ordinary demon.
那不是普通妖怪
I'm going to protect you, even if we end up in shreds.
我會保護你的 即便我們最終化為碎片
Let's play, just like our carefree old days.
我們像無憂無慮的從前一樣玩耍吧
There's someone else in this room!
這個房間裡還有一個人！
-Where did Madame Ryu go? -I must find Hong-joo.
-柳閣長去哪裡了？ -我必須找到紅朱
What if this is a trap?
如果這是個陷阱呢？
At least, we'll know why Moo-yeong came to see me.
我們至少會知道無影來見我的原因
The Path of the Damned.
詛咒之路
It's somewhere even Taluipa can't peek into!
那是連奪衣婆都無法窺探的地方！
Yeon, please be my pawn.
阿硯，請你做我的棋子吧
I can't die here…
我不能死在這裡…
TRANSLATED BY MYSTERIOUS STRANGER
字幕翻譯：鄒琳